Okay, so one of the common
tools used for performance
reporting is this one
called a Canban board.
And especially in an agile environment,
canband boards are used a lot,
also known as a task board.
Now, it doesn't have to be used in Agile,
it could be really used in any kind of
project, but at a glance it's showing the
performance, like where we're at,
what work has been started, what work is
left to start, what work is being
completed and so and so forth and it can
be used as a type of information radiator
as well as one of the charts that you
would use as part of your information
radiator along with other charts to show
the progress of your team to show your
stakeholders the progress of your team
right and then this could be located in a
prominent part of you know where your team
is located where your team is working
right if you're in in the office
environment or if team members are working
remotely then it would be part of a
dashboard somewhere, right?
So any stakeholder can identify,
they can see, okay, so this is a progress,
this is a status, this is how the team is
it is progressing.
And so one of those
charts and this one known as
a Canban board, also
known as a task board, right?
You could see either of those terms.
So this is a very simple example then of a
Canban board or a task board.
And basically, you can see it's very
visual.
at a glance is showing all
the work that has started,
all the work that needs to
be done, and so and so forth.
And you can see these are all kind of like
post-it notes.
You can have post-it notes.
They can have many different ways of doing
this, right?
Sometimes it's just a list.
If it's electronic, then obviously it'll
just be a list.
You won't necessarily have post-it notes.
But if it's something physical,
you may have post-it notes showing the
tasks that have started and what's left to
do, what's been completed.
and so and so forth.
That's a very simple example here then.
This is an agile environment.
You'd have your user story.
What are all the tasks to make up this
user story?
So you have the to-do.
These tasks have not started yet.
Right.
So we can see, these are all the ones that
are outstanding.
They have not even been started yet.
These are the tasks that are in progress,
right?
This work in progress.
So this is what the team is working on
right now.
They're working on all of these different
tasks.
So these tasks have almost been done.
They just need to be tested, right?
So there's another column here to verify.
We need to make sure then these tasks,
we've basically completed them,
but they're just kind of in a testing
phase.
We're just testing them, making sure that
it's completely done.
So whoever needs to verify, a sign off,
then that's really what that refers to.
And then the last column, done.
So these tasks have been complete.
These tasks meet the definition of done,
and so they are now complete.
So at a glance now, at
a glance, any state code
that can look at the
status of this project.
They can look at the, or in this case,
a sprint.
They can look at the status of this sprint
and see, okay, so these are the chasts
that still need to be started or they're
working on all of these.
These are all complete.
Now, also, though, one of the other
important things about Canban,
Camban board, and one of the other lean
principles as well, which
is also utilising agile.
and that is you don't want to have too
many tasks that are work in progress you
don't want to have too many tasks open at
the same time otherwise they'll never get
done so you want to basically have an
optimum number of tasks that your team is
going to be working on so you may have
another column that's showing the cap
right so the work in progress cap right
this is a maximum number of activities
that maximum number of tasks that we can
have open So let's just say, for example,
sake of argument four,
right, we cannot have
more than four activities
open at once, right?
Otherwise, if we start having six,
seven, eight, ten activities that we're
all working on at the same time,
when are they going to get done?
You're going to end up having tons and
tons of activities that are in progress
and then nothing that's in the complete
stage.
So that's not very efficient.
So you want to make sure then that you
only have a certain number of tasks open.
So you're going to have a cap.
This is a maximum that you want.
But at the same time, at the
other end of the scale, you
don't just want to be working
on one task at a time either.
If you're just working on one task, once
that's complete, then
we'll start another task.
Well, there might be a lot of
inefficiencies there as well.
There might be a lot of
time wastage there that
you can alleviate by
starting another task.
right so you want to strike a balance so
during release planning your team your or
rather the agile team the team facilitator
the product owner will be discussing
amongst themselves they'll they'll agree
what is a maximum number of tasks that we
can have open and that will be our cap
right we're not going to have any more
tasks open than that so anyway so this is
an example of a canband board then so
again at a glance anybody can look at this
any stakeholder we'll look at this and
have a good understanding of the progress
of the team.